A Guide to the Timberlake Family Papers, 1762-2009
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Timberlake Family Papers, 1762-2009
The Library of Virginia
45491
10 cubic feet (25 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Donald H. C. Timberlake, Sabattus, Maine and Betty Bowe Timberlake, Morristown, Tennessee.
Biographical Information
Archibald Burnett Timberlake (1809-1863) married Emily Rushbrook Bowe (1807-1836) on 7 June 1832. Their son, John Henry Timberlake, was born on 23 August 1835. He attended the University of Virginia (B.A., 1857; M.A., 1858) and was a teacher at Southwood Academy in Talladega, Alabama. He then served with the 4th Virginia Cavalry during the Civil War. On 12 November 1863, he married his cousin, Etta Gertrude Bowe (1838-1911), daughter of Nathaniel Fleming Bowe (1809-1875) and Marietta Chiles (Crenshaw) Bowe (1814-1840), and they resided at "Rutland," Atlee, Hanover County, Virginia. John Henry Timberlake died on 11 February 1900 and Etta Gertrude Bowe Timberlake died on 25 May 1911. They are buried in Hollywood Cemetery in Richmond.
Their daughter, Carrie Crenshaw Timberlake, was born on 29 October 1864. She attended Wesleyan Female Institute in Staunton, Virginia, Richmond College, and later studied German and French abroad. She taught at Belhaven College in Jackson, Mississippi, Lewisburg Female Institute in Lewisburg, West Virginia, and the Stonewall Jackson Institute in Abingdon, Virginia. Carrie C. Timberlake traveled extensively throughout Europe and Asia following her teaching career. She never married, and died at "Rutland" on 15 March 1938. She is buried in Hollywood Cemetery.
Her brother, Maury Cullen Timberlake, was born on 16 May 1878. He married Ruby Franklin Beach (1884-1948) on 14 October 1903. Maury C. Timberlake died on 11 June 1935 and is buried in Hollywood Cemetery. Following his death, Ruby Timberlake married Andrew Burnett West.
Maury and Ruby's son, Donald Crenshaw Timberlake, was born on 5 December 1915. He attended Virginia Polytechnic Institute (B.S. 1938), and served as an Army officer during World War II. He married Ethel Lee Culley (1916-2009) on 9 July 1938. Donald C. Timberlake died on 11 February 2007 and Lee Timberlake died on 4 September 2009. They are buried in Hollywood Cemetery. Donald and Lee's children, Donald Henry Crenshaw Timberlake and Betty Bowe Timberlake, donated these Family Papers to the Library of Virginia in 2011.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1762-2009, of the Timberlake family of Atlee, Hanover County, Virginia. Includes correspondence and subject files, mainly of John Henry Timberlake (1835-1900) and his wife Etta Gertrude (Bowe) Timberlake (1838-1911), and their daughter Carrie Crenshaw Timberlake (1864-1938).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Correspondence.
II. Subject Files.
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1840-1981., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 1-7)
  The correspondence is divided into three groups. The first group covers the years 1840-1981. It includes letters written by John H. Timberlake to his cousin and future wife Etta Gertrude Bowe while he was teaching at Southwood Academy in Talladega, Alabama, and later while he was serving with the 4th Virginia Cavalry at Culpeper Courthouse, Brandy Station, Yorktown, Richmond, Hanover County, Martinsburg, and Spotsylvania Courthouse. Of particular note is a letter, dated 4 July 1862, in which he mentions his action as an escort and guide for General Stonewall Jackson to Cold Harbor. There are transcriptions for these letters which cover the years 1858 to 1863. Also included in this group are letters of sympathy written upon the death of John H. Timberlake (1900) and Etta Gertrude Timberlake (1911). There are also numerous letters written to Carrie Crenshaw Timberlake from friends in Germany and France. Much of the post-1900 correspondence is between Gertrude and Carrie while the latter was teaching at Lewisburg Female Institute, and contain information regarding Gertrude's activities in the United Daughters of the Confederacy, including conventions she atttended in Norfolk and San Francisco, as well as her visit to the Lewis and Clark Exposition in Portland, Oregon in 1905. There are also descriptions of trips by Gertrude to Jamestown and Nashville, Tennessee. There are numerous letters to Carrie concerning her interest in genealogy from fellow researchers, and also relating to her finances and investments. Also included in this group are letters written by Donald C. Timberlake (1915-2007) to his wife Ethel Lee (Culley) Timberlake (1916-2009), while he was serving in the Army in Italy during World War II.
  The second group of letters covers the years 1871 to 1911, and includes many letters from her parents to Carrie while she was attending Wesleyan Female Institute in Staunton, and later teaching in Botetourt County, Virginia. The correspondence from 1896-1897 is between them while Carrie was studying overseas in Hannover, Germany and Paris, France. There are also letters written by John H. Timberlake in 1899 while he was in Hot Springs, Virginia, and Asheville, North Carolina for health reasons. The post-1900 letters are mainly between Gertrude and Carrie while the latter was teaching in Lewisburg and the Stonewall Jackson Institute in Abingdon, Virginia, as well as when she was on trips to England and Scotland and also out west at Yellowstone. There are transcriptions for some of these letters.
  The third group of letters covers the years 1896 to 1898 and 1901 to 1903. It includes letters written by Carrie to her parents while she was studying in Germany, as well as visiting Italy and France. She also kept two letterbooks containing the text of these letters. These two volumes can be found in the Subject Files. The 1901-1903 correspondence are letters written to Ruby Franklin Beach (1884-1948) prior to her marriage to Maury Cullen Timberlake (1878-1935).
  - 1840. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1853. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1858. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1859. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1860. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1861. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1862. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1863. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1858-1863 (Transcriptions). (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1869. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1870. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1872. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1873. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1875. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1876. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1877. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1879. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1889. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1890. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1895. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1897. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1898. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1899. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1900. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1900 (Sympathy Letters - Death of John H. Timberlake). (Box 1, Folder 25-28)
  - 1900 (Sympathy Letters - Death of John H. Timberlake). (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1900 (Resolutions - Death of John H. Timberlake). (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1901. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1903. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1904. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1905. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1906. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1907. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1908. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1909. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1910. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1911. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1911 (Sympathy Letters - Death of Etta Gertrude Timberlake). (Box 2, Folder 13-15)
  - 1913. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1914. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1915. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1916. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1917. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1918. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1919. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1920. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 1921. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 1922. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 1923. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 1924. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 1925. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1926. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1927. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1928. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1929. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1931. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1932 (January-June). (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1932 (July-December). (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1933. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1934. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1935 (January-August). (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1935 (September-December). (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1936 (January-March). (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1936 (April-June). (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1936 (July-December). (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1937 (January-June). (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1937 (July). (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1937 (August-December). (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1938. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1941. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1942-1945 (Letters of Donald C. Timberlake During World War II). (Box 4, Folder 6-9)
  - 1948. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1959. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1960. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1981. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - n.d.. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 1871-1881. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1882-1883. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1886-1888. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1890-1895. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1896. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1897. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 1898-1899. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 1902-1904. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1905 (January-June). (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 1905 (July-August). (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 1906 (January-June). (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 1906 (September-December). (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 1907-1909. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1910 (May-August). (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1910 (September-December). (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1911. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 1896-1898 (Letters from Carrie C. Timberlake While in Germany). (Box 7, Folder 1-7)
  - 1901, 1903, n.d. (Letters to Ruby Franklin Beach). (Box 7, Folder 8-11)
- Series II. Subject Files, 1762-2009., Extent: 18 boxes. (Box 8-25)
  The subject files contain a variety of materials relating to the activities of the Timberlake family. There is information relating to the Army service of Donald C. Timberlake during World War II, autograph albums, historical information on Atlee, Atlee's Station, Cool Spring Baptist Church, and Washington-Henry Academy, Bible records, books, and botanical samples collected by Carrie C. Timberlake, and clippings. There are Civil War papers of John H. Timberlake, including a discharge, furlough, oath, and ladies' pass for Gertrude Bowe. The subject files also contain a large amount of material relating to Carrie's extensive travel, including cruise books, menus, passenger lists, programs and itineraries, tickets and passes, tourist brochures and guide books, and a travel journal. There are also deeds, diplomas, estate papers, genealogical notes on the Anderson, Bowe, Carr, Chiles, Clopton, Crenshaw, Dabney, Davis, Garland, Graves, Hill, Meredith, Shelton, Timberlake, and Tinsley families, letters of recommendation, obituaries, plats and surveys, photographs, poetry, postcards, recipe books, and scrapbooks. Finally, there is information relating to the development of the Timberlake home "Rutland" into a mixed-use residential community, and also information on the family's investments and rental properties, and also tax records. Of note are four volumes of tax books (1841, 1844, 1845, 1847) kept by Archibald Burnett Timberlake (1809-1863).
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1831-1937. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Affidavit, 1762. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Agreement. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Album of Verses, 1821-1832. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Album of Verses - Marietta Chiles Crenshaw. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - The American Gardener, Containing Ample Directions for Working a Kitchen Garden Every Month in the Year..., Georgetown, 1818. (Box 18)
  - Army Records - Donald Crenshaw Timberlake. (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
  - Atlee/Atlee's Station. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Atlee History Newsletter. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Autograph Album - Etta Gertrude Bowe. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Autograph Album (Germany), 1898. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Barn Sketch. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Battle of Atlee Station. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Belhaven College. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Bible Records. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Birnie Statements, 1935-1936. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Book Catalogues. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Botanical Samples. (Box 9, Folder 6-8)
  - Bowe Collections at UNC-Chapel Hill and Duke University. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Bowe vs. Haller - Copy of Judgment, 1808. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - C & O Railroad. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Card Index (Hanover County History) by David L. Timberlake. (Box 22)
  - Census - Hanover County. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Chesapeake and Ohio Land Improvement Company. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Children's Language Books and Primers. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Clippings. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Coal Mine Property - Deed, 1867. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Confederate Currency. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Cool Spring Baptist Church. (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Cruise Books. (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Cruise Menus and Passenger Lists. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Cruise Programs and Itineraries. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Cruise Tickets and Passes. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - D.A.R./S.A.R.. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Davis, Mary Moore (Kewpies). (Box 10, Folder 5-8)
  - Deeds. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Deeds to be Researched. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Descendants of Benjamin Timberlake. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Diplomas. (Box 25)
  - Discours sur l'histoire Universelle by Jacques-Benigne Bossuet. (Box 18)
  - Electric Bills. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - English, Sara John. (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
  - English, Sara John. (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
  - Engravings. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Ephemera. (Box 21)
  - Estate of Lelia T. Beach. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Estate of John Bowe. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Estate of Nathaniel Bowe. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Estate of Nathaniel Fleming Bowe. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Estate of William Bowe. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Estate of Carrie Crenshaw Timberlake. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Estate of John Henry Timberlake. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Estate of Ruby Franklin West. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Expense Ledger, 1895-1897. (Box 18)
  - Foreign Currency. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Foreign Travel Document (unidentified). (Box 25)
  - Funeral Programs, 2007, 2009. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Furlough, 1864. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Genealogical Charts. (Box 25)
  - Genealogical Notes. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Genealogical Notes - Anderson. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Genealogical Notes - Bowe. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Genealogical Notes - Bowes. (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Genealogical Notes - Bowie. (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Genealogical Notes - Carr. (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Genealogical Notes - Chiles. (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Genealogical Notes - Clopton. (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Genealogical Notes - Crenshaw. (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Genealogical Notes - Dabney. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Genealogical Notes - Davis. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Genealogical Notes - Garland. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Genealogical Notes - Graves. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Genealogical Notes - Hill. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Genealogical Notes - Meredith. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Genealogical Notes - Shelton. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Genealogical Notes - Timberlake. (Box 12, Folder 8-10)
  - Genealogical Notes - Tinsley. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Greeting Cards. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Guardian's Accounts - Hector Bowe. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Historical Hanover County, Virginia, 1720-1926. (Box 25)
  - Hotel Bills, 1929. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Hotel Stationary. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Insurance. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Insurance - 2706 Fourth Avenue, 1937. (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Inventories, 1938. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Iran (Donald H.C. Timberlake, United States Peace Corps), 1967-1969. (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Jackson, Stonewall. (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Land Grants. (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Robert E. Lee Property - Lumberton, NC, 1934-1937. (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Letterbooks of Carrie Crenshaw Timberlake (2 vols.), 1896-1898. (Box 18)
  - Letters of Recommendation (Carrie C. Timberlake). (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Letters of Recommendation (John H. Timberlake). (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Marriage Certificate (Timberlake/Culley), 1938. (Box 25)
  - Mechanicsville. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Military Discharge Certificate, 1863. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Military Pass (Ladies Pass), 1864. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Militia Appointments, 1797, 1820. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Militia List, 1810. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Newspapers - Portions of a Japanese Newspaper, "Christian Observer" (1881), "Richmond Christian Advocate" (1887), and "Richmond Times-Dispatch" (1997). (Box 25)
  - Nolting First Mortgage Corporation - Bond, 1933-1937. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Novum Testamentum Domini nostri Jesu Christi: Inteprete Theodoro Beza, London, 1788. (Box 18)
  - Oath of Allegiance. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Obituaries. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Order for Oats, 1787. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Passport - Carrie Crenshaw Timberlake, 1896. (Box 25)
  - Passport - David Leslie Timberlake, 1937. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Peter Rabbit. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Photograph Albums (empty). (Box 23)
  - Photographic Glimpses of New Orleans, 1902. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Photographs. (Box 24)
  - Photographs - "Magnolia" (Nathaniel Fleming Bowe Residence, Richmond) and Donald H.C. and Betty Bowe Timberlake. (Box 25)
  - Picture Frame. (Box 23)
  - The Pilgrim Scrip, March 1928. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Plats and Surveys. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Playbill, 1895. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Poetry and Music. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Portraits - John H. Timberlake and Etta Gertrude Timberlake. (Box 25)
  - Postcard Albums (empty). (Box 23)
  - Postcards. (Box 22)
  - Programs. (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Promissory Notes. (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Puller, May T.. (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Ragland Castle. (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Recipe Book. (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Recipe Book (Etta Gertrude Timberlake). (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Redd, Martha W. - Loan Papers, 1928-1935. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Rent Accounts - 2706 Fourth Avenue, 1936-1937. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Repairs - 2706 Fourth Avenue, 1935-1937. (Box 14, Folder 4-5)
  - Report Cards. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Richmond College. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Robertson, James I. - Virginia Tech. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - The Rudiments of the Latin Tongue: or a Plain and Easy Introduction to Latin Grammar...," by William Mann, A.M., Philadelphia, 1844. (Box 18)
  - "Rutland" Development, 2008. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - "Rutland" Development - Clubhouse Elevations, 2006. (Box 25)
  - "Rutland" Development - Plats and Surveys. (Map-case 2, Drawer 12)
  - "Rutland" Graveyard (Olin C. Nolley Sketch). (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - "Rutland" - Removal of Remains in Cemetery, 2005. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Scrapbook. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbook (Illustrations and Poetry). (Box 23)
  - Silhouette - Nathaniel Fleming Bowe. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Silhouettes - Alice Bowe Colonna and Carrie C. Timberlake. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Speech - Timberlake Portraits Presentation. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Speech - United Daughters of the Confederacy. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Southwood Select School (Talladega, Ala.). (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Stonewall Jackson College (Abingdon, Va.). (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Tax Books - Hanover County (4 vols.), 1841, 1844, 1845, 1847. (Box 20)
  - Tax Records from Old Tax Books. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Tax Returns, 1931-1937. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1865-1869. (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1870-1879. (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1880-1889. (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1890-1899. (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1900-1909. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1910-1919. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1920-1929. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1930-1939. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts - Boyd Street, 1914-1922. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts - "Meredith's" and "Magnolia," 1898-1913. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts - "Rutland" - Carrie C. Timberlake, 1912-1936. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Teacher's Certificate, 1958. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Thomson, Lelia C. T.. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Timberlake, Archibald Burnett - Biographical Information. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Timberlake, David L. - Drawings. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Timberlake Family Bible. (Box 19)
  - Timberlakes of Port Royal. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Tourist Information - Ceylon. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Tourist Information - China. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Tourist Information - Cuba. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Tourist Information - Egypt. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Tourist Information - Germany. (Box 15, Folder 17-18)
  - Tourist Information - Great Britain. (Box 15, Folder 19-20)
  - Tourist Information - Hawaii. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Tourist Information - India. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Tourist Information - Italy. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Tourist Information - Japan. (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
  - Tourist Information - Korea. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Tourist Information - Panama Canal. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Tourist Information - Philippines. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Tourist Information - Switzerland. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Tourist Information - United States. (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
  - Tourist Information - United States. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Travel Diary. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - A True and Strange Discourse on the Travailes of Two English Pilgrims by Henry Timberlake, London, 1620. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Typing Expenses. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Washington-Henry Academy. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Washington-Henry Academy - School Record, 1879-1882. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Washington-Henry Academy - Trustee's Minute Book, 1911-1915. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Washington-Henry Gazette, 1933-1935. (Box 25)
  - Wedding Invitation (Timberlake/Bowe), 1863. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Wesleyan Female Institute (Staunton, Va.). (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - "When I Was a Boy in Eastern Hanover County During the 1920's and Early 1930's" by Donald C. Timberlake. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Will of Elizabeth Ann Bowe. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Will of Nathaniel F. Bowe. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Will of Mary F. Boyd. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Will of Charles Graves (portion). (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Will of Archibald Burnett Timberlake. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Will of Carrie Crenshaw Timberlake. (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Will of David Timberlake. (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Will of Francis Timberlake. (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Will of W.W. Timberlake. (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Will of Mary Washington. (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Will of Ruby Franklin West. (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - World's Fair Scenes, 1894. (Box 25)